<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<nlmSearchResult>
  <term>symptoms</term>
  <file>viv_jRMRW4</file>
  <server>pvlb7srch16</server>
  <count>733</count>
  <retstart>0</retstart>
  <retmax>10</retmax>
  <list num="733" start="0" per="10">
    <document rank="0" url="https://medlineplus.gov/dualdiagnosis.html">
      <content name="title">Dual &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Diagnosis&lt;/span&gt;</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">What is dual &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;diagnosis&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;p&gt;If you have a dual &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;diagnosis&lt;/span&gt;, that means that you have both a mental disorder and a substance use disorder (SUD), either with alcohol or drugs. A dual &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;diagnosis&lt;/span&gt; is a type of comorbidity, which is when someone has two disorders at the same time. Another name for this is co-occurring disorders.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Mental and substance use disorders often occur together. Many people who develop SUDs are also diagnosed with mental disorders. And the reverse is true; many people with mental disorders will develop an SUD. Having both types of disorders is even more common in teenagers, people with serious mental illness, and people with certain mental disorders.&lt;/p&gt;Why do substance use disorders and mental disorders occur together?&lt;p&gt;Although these problems often occur together, this does not mean that one caused the other, even if one appeared first. In fact, it can be hard to figure out which came first. Researchers think that there are three possible reasons as to why they often occur together:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Common risk factors can contribute to both mental disorders and SUDs. These factors include:
  &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Genetics.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stress.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trauma, especially in childhood. Veterans with post-traumatic stress disorder (PTSD) are also at risk for SUDs&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mental disorders can contribute to drug use and SUDs. For example, people with mental disorders may use drugs or alcohol to try to feel better temporarily. This is known as self-medication. Also, mental disorders may change the brain to make it more likely that you will become addicted.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Substance use and addiction can contribute to the development of a mental disorder. Substance use may change the brain in ways that make you more likely to develop a mental disorder.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the treatments for dual &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;diagnosis&lt;/span&gt;?&lt;p&gt;If you have a dual &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;diagnosis&lt;/span&gt;, it is usually better to treat both conditions at the same time rather than separately. You and your health care provider can work on a treatment plan that fits your needs.The plan should take into account your age, which substance(s) you are misusing, and which specific mental disorder(s) you have. The plan may include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Behavioral therapy, such as talk therapy (psychotherapy), long-term residential treatment (which combines housing and treatment services), and therapies to help you stay motivated to stick with your treatment plan.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Medicines. There are effective medicines that treat opioid, alcohol, and nicotine addiction. There are also medicines that can lessen the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of many mental disorders. Some medicines may treat more than one disorder.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A referral to a support group. Support groups can give you emotional and social support. They are also a place where people can share tips about how to deal with day-to-day challenges.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute on Drug Abuse&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">&lt;span class="qt1"&gt;Diagnosis&lt;/span&gt;, Dual (Psychiatry)</content>
      <content name="groupName">Mental Health and Behavior</content>
      <content name="groupName">Substance Use and Disorders</content>
      <content name="snippet">What is dual &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;diagnosis&lt;/span&gt;? If you have a dual &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;diagnosis&lt;/span&gt;, that means that you have both a mental disorder and a substance use disorder (SUD), either with alcohol  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="1" url="https://medlineplus.gov/asthma.html">
      <content name="title">Asthma</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Bronchial Asthma</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">What is asthma?&lt;p&gt;Asthma is a chronic (long-term) lung disease. It affects your airways, the tubes that carry air in and out of your lungs. When you have asthma, your airways can become inflamed and narrowed. This can cause wheezing, coughing, and tightness in your chest. When these &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; get worse than usual, it is called an asthma attack or flare-up.&lt;/p&gt;What causes asthma?&lt;p&gt;The exact cause of asthma is unknown. Genetics and your environment likely play a role in who gets asthma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An asthma attack can happen when you are exposed to an asthma trigger. An asthma trigger is something that can set off or worsen your asthma &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;. Different triggers can cause different types of asthma:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allergic asthma is caused by allergens. Allergens are substances that cause an allergic reaction. They can include
	&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dust mites&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mold&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pets&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pollen from grass, trees, and weeds&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Waste from pests such as cockroaches and mice&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nonallergic asthma is caused by triggers that are not allergens, such as
	&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Breathing in cold air&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Certain medicines&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Household chemicals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Infections such as colds and the flu&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Outdoor air pollution&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tobacco smoke&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Occupational asthma is caused by breathing in chemicals or industrial dusts at work&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Exercise-induced asthma happens during physical exercise, especially when the air is dry&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asthma triggers may be different for each person and can change over time.&lt;/p&gt;Who is at risk for asthma?&lt;p&gt;Asthma affects people of all ages, but it often starts during childhood. Certain factors can raise your risk of having asthma:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being exposed to secondhand smoke when your mother is pregnant with you or when you are a small child&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being exposed to certain substances at work, such as chemical irritants or industrial dusts&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Genetics and family history. You are more likely to have asthma if one of your parents has it, especially if it's your mother.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Race or ethnicity. Black and African Americans and Puerto Ricans are at higher risk of asthma than people of other races or ethnicities.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having other diseases or conditions such as obesity and allergies&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Often having viral respiratory infections as a young child&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sex. In children, asthma is more common in boys. In teens and adults, it is more common in women.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of asthma?&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of asthma include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chest tightness&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Coughing, especially at night or early morning&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Shortness of breath&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wheezing, which causes a whistling sound when you breathe out&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;These &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; can range from mild to severe. You may have them every day or only once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When you are having an asthma attack, your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; get much worse. The attacks may come on gradually or suddenly. Sometimes they can be life-threatening. They are more common in people who have severe asthma. If you are having asthma attacks, you may need a change in your treatment.&lt;/p&gt;How is asthma diagnosed?&lt;p&gt;Your health care provider may use many tools to diagnose asthma:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Physical exam&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Medical history&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lung function tests, including spirometry, to test how well your lungs work&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tests to measure how your airways react to specific exposures. During this test, you inhale different concentrations of allergens or medicines that may tighten the muscles in your airways. Spirometry is done before and after the test.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Peak expiratory flow (PEF) tests to measure how fast you can blow air out using maximum effort&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fractional exhaled nitric oxide (FeNO) tests to measure levels of nitric oxide in your breath when you breathe out. High levels of nitric oxide may mean that your lungs are inflamed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allergy skin or blood tests, if you have a history of allergies. These tests check which allergens cause a reaction from your immune system.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the treatments for asthma?&lt;p&gt;If you have asthma, you will work with your health care provider to create a treatment plan. The plan will include ways to manage your asthma &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; and prevent asthma attacks. It will include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Strategies to avoid triggers. For example, if tobacco smoke is a trigger for you, you should not smoke or allow other people to smoke in your home or car.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Short-term relief medicines,  also called quick-relief medicines. They help prevent &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; or relieve &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; during an asthma attack. They include an inhaler to carry with you all the time. It may also include other types of medicines which work quickly to help open your airways.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Control medicines.  You take them every day to help prevent &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;. They work by reducing airway inflammation and preventing narrowing of the airways.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have a severe attack and the short-term relief medicines do not work, you will need emergency care.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your provider may adjust your treatment until asthma &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; are controlled.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes asthma is severe and cannot be controlled with other treatments. If you are an adult with uncontrolled asthma, in some cases your provider might suggest bronchial thermoplasty. This is a procedure that uses heat to shrink the smooth muscle in the lungs. Shrinking the muscle reduces your airway's ability to tighten and allows you to breathe more easily. The procedure has some risks, so it's important to discuss them with your provider.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Asthma</content>
      <content name="groupName">Lungs and Breathing</content>
      <content name="groupName">Immune System</content>
      <content name="snippet">What is asthma? Asthma is a chronic (long-term) lung disease. It affects your airways, the tubes that carry air in and out of your lungs. When you have  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="2" url="https://medlineplus.gov/asthmainchildren.html">
      <content name="title">Asthma in Children</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Childhood Asthma</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Pediatric asthma</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">What is asthma? &lt;p&gt;Asthma is a chronic (long-term) lung disease. It affects your airways, the tubes that carry air in and out of your lungs. When you have asthma, your airways can become inflamed and narrowed. This can cause wheezing, coughing, and tightness in your chest. When these &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; get worse than usual, it is called an asthma attack or flare-up.&lt;/p&gt;How does asthma affect children? &lt;p&gt;Asthma often starts during childhood, usually before age 5. Many children have asthma - it is the most common chronic disease of childhood. It can cause children to miss school and end up in the hospital. But treatments can help manage asthma.&lt;/p&gt;What causes asthma in children?&lt;p&gt;The exact cause of asthma is unknown. Genetics and environment likely play a role in which children get asthma.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;An asthma attack can happen when your child is exposed to an asthma trigger. An asthma trigger is something that can set off or worsen asthma &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;. Different triggers can cause different types of asthma:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allergic asthma is caused by allergens. Allergens are substances that cause an allergic reaction. They can include
	&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dust mites&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mold&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pets&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pollen from grass, trees, and weeds&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Waste from pests such as cockroaches and mice&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nonallergic asthma is caused by triggers that are not allergens, such as
	&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Breathing in cold air&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Certain medicines&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Household chemicals&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Infections such as colds and the flu&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Outdoor air pollution&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tobacco smoke&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Exercise-induced asthma happens during physical exercise, especially when the air is dry&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Asthma triggers may be different for each child and can change over time.&lt;/p&gt;Which children are at risk for asthma?&lt;p&gt;Certain factors raise the risk of asthma in children:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being exposed to secondhand smoke when their mother is pregnant with them or when they are small children&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Genetics and family history. Children are more likely to have asthma if one of their parents has it, especially if it's the mother. &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Race or ethnicity. Black and African Americans and Puerto Ricans are at higher risk of asthma than people of other races or ethnicities.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having other diseases or conditions such as  obesity and allergies&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Often having viral respiratory infections as young children&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sex. In children, asthma is more common in boys. In teens, it is more common in girls.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of asthma in children?&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of asthma in children include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chest tightness&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Coughing, especially at night or early morning&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Breathing problems, such as shortness of breath, rapid breathing, or gasping for air&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Feeling tired&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dark circles under the eyes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being irritable&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wheezing, which causes a whistling sound when they breathe out&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trouble eating or sucking (in infants)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;These &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; can range from mild to severe. They may happen often or only once in a while.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;When children have an asthma attack, their &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; get much worse. The attacks may come on gradually or suddenly. Sometimes they can be life-threatening. Warning signs of a severe attack include severe coughing, serious breathing problems, and turning very pale or blue in the face, lips and/or fingernails. If your child has those &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;, get medical help right away.&lt;/p&gt;How is asthma in children diagnosed?&lt;p&gt;It can be hard to diagnose asthma in children, especially if they are young. Asthma has similar &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; as other childhood conditions. And some children may not have asthma &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; very often, so it may seem like they are having respiratory infections instead.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your child's health care provider may use many tools to diagnose asthma:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Physical exam&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Medical history&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chest x-ray&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lung function tests, including spirometry, to test how well the lungs work. Younger children are usually not able to do these tests.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Allergy skin or blood tests, if you have a history of allergies. These tests check which allergens cause a reaction from your immune system.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have a young child who cannot do lung function tests, the provider may suggest doing a trial of asthma medicines. The trial involves giving your child the medicines for several weeks to see whether the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; get better.&lt;/p&gt;What are the treatments for asthma in children?&lt;p&gt;If your child has asthma, you will work with their health care provider to create a treatment plan. The plan will include ways to manage your child's asthma &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; and prevent asthma attacks, such as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Strategies to avoid triggers. For example, if tobacco smoke is a trigger for your child, you should not allow anyone to smoke in your home or car.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Short-term relief medicines, also called quick-relief medicines. They help prevent &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; or relieve &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; during an asthma attack. They include an inhaler to have for your child at all times. It may also include other types of medicines which work quickly to help open your child's airways.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Control medicines.  They work by reducing airway inflammation and preventing narrowing of the airways. Not all children will take control medicines. Whether or not your child needs them depends on how severe the asthma is and how often your child has &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your child has a severe attack and the short-term relief medicines do not work, get medical help right away.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your child's provider may adjust the treatment until the asthma &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; are controlled.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Asthma</content>
      <content name="groupName">Children and Teenagers</content>
      <content name="groupName">Lungs and Breathing</content>
      <content name="groupName">Immune System</content>
      <content name="snippet">What is asthma?  Asthma is a chronic (long-term) lung disease. It affects your airways, the tubes that carry air in and out of your lungs. When you have  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="3" url="https://medlineplus.gov/atrialfibrillation.html">
      <content name="title">Atrial Fibrillation</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">AF</content>
      <content name="altTitle">AFib</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">What is atrial fibrillation (AFib)?&lt;p&gt;Atrial fibrillation, also known as AFib or AF, is one of the most common types of arrhythmias.  Arrhythmias are problems with the rate or rhythm of your heartbeat. They can cause your heart to beat too slowly, too fast, or in an irregular way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have AFib, your heart beats irregularly and sometimes much faster than normal. Also, your heart's upper and lower chambers do not work together as they should. When this happens, the lower chambers do not fill completely or pump enough blood to your lungs and body. This can cause &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; such as dizziness, fatigue, and a pounding heartbeat.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;AFib may happen in brief episodes, or it may be a permanent condition. It's very important to treat it, since AFib can put you at risk for stroke and other heart conditions.&lt;/p&gt;What causes atrial fibrillation (AFib)?&lt;p&gt;AFib is most often caused by changes to the heart's tissue or the electrical signaling that helps the heartbeat. These changes can happen due to different conditions and factors, such as high blood pressure, coronary artery disease, congenital heart defects, infections, and aging. Sometimes the cause is unknown.&lt;/p&gt;Who is more likely to develop atrial fibrillation (AFib)?&lt;p&gt;Anyone can develop AFib, but there are certain things that raise your risk for it:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Aging. The risk of atrial fibrillation increases as you get older, especially when you are over age 65.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Family history and genetics. AFib can run in families. So can heart disease, which raises your risk of AFib.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Some lifestyle choices. Your risk is higher if you drink a lot of alcohol, use certain illegal drugs such as cocaine and methamphetamines, or smoke.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having certain health conditions, such as:
  &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;High blood pressure&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Diabetes&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Heart failure&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Heart valve diseases&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Obesity&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Hyperthyroidism&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chronic kidney disease&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;COPD and other lung diseases&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sleep apnea&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Race. AFib is more common in people with European ancestry.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Recent surgery. You may be at risk of atrial fibrillation in the early days and weeks after surgery on your heart, lungs, or esophagus.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of atrial fibrillation (AFib)?&lt;p&gt;Some people who have AFib don't have any &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; and don't know they have it. If you do have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;, you may only notice them once in a while. Or you may have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; that are more frequent. And in some cases, the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; might be severe. If you have heart disease, you are more likely to notice your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms. And those symptoms&lt;/span&gt; could get worse if your heart disease gets worse.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of AFib can include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Extreme fatigue, which is the most common &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptom&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Heart palpitations (the feeling that your heart is skipping a beat, fluttering, pounding, or beating too hard or too fast)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Trouble breathing, especially when lying down or when exercising&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chest pain&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dizziness or fainting&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Low blood pressure&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What other problems can AFib cause?&lt;p&gt;If AFib is not treated, it can lead to serious health problems (complications) such as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stroke&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Heart failure&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Blood clots&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sudden cardiac arrest (SCA)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cognitive impairment and dementia&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help prevent these problems, it's important to contact your health care provider if you are having &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;. If you do have AFib, the sooner you are diagnosed and treated, the better.&lt;/p&gt;How is atrial fibrillation (AFib) diagnosed?&lt;p&gt;To find out if you have AFib, your provider:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Will ask about your medical history, including your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;, lifestyle, and any other health conditions you may have&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Will ask about your family history, to find out if you have relatives who have or had AFib&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Will do a physical exam&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;May order blood tests&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Will likely order heart tests, such as an electrocardiogram (also called an EKG or ECG) and echocardiogram&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;May ask you to wear a heart monitor device that records your heart's electrical activity&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the treatments for atrial fibrillation (AFib)?&lt;p&gt;The treatments for AFib may include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Blood thinner medicines that help prevent blood clots from forming.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Medicines to control your heart's rhythm and rate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Following heart-healthy lifestyle changes, such as:
  &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Following a heart-healthy eating plan that limits saturated fats, salt, and cholesterol. An example is the DASH eating plan.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Limiting or avoiding alcohol, because it can increase your heart rate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Aiming for a healthy weight.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Getting regular physical activity.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Managing stress.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Quitting smoking.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Procedures such as:
  &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Electrical cardioversion, which restores your heart rhythm using low-energy shocks to your heart.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Catheter ablation, which scars the tissue that is causing the arrhythmia. The scar tissue blocks the abnormal heart signals.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Surgeries such as:
  &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Surgery to put in a pacemaker to help control the arrhythmia.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A Maze procedure, which creates scar tissue in a maze-like pattern in certain parts of the heart.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Left atrial appendage closure, a surgery on a small sac in the muscle wall of your left atrium (the upper left chamber of your heart). It helps prevent blood clots and can reduce your risk of stroke. This surgery is for people who are not able to take blood thinners.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Can atrial fibrillation (AFib) be prevented?&lt;p&gt;There are steps you can take to help lower your risk of atrial fibrillation, such as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Making heart-healthy lifestyle changes:
  &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Following a heart-healthy eating plan&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Limiting or avoiding alcohol&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Aiming for a healthy weight&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Getting regular physical activity&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Managing stress&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Not smoking&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Avoiding illegal drugs, such as cocaine and methamphetamines&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Taking antiarrhythmic medicine (medicine to treat arrhythmia) if you are having heart surgery&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Treating any health conditions that could raise your risk of AFib&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Atrial Fibrillation</content>
      <content name="groupName">Blood, Heart and Circulation</content>
      <content name="snippet">What is atrial fibrillation (AFib)? Atrial fibrillation, also known as AFib or AF, is one of the most common types of arrhythmias.  Arrhythmias are problems  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="4" url="https://medlineplus.gov/attentiondeficithyperactivitydisorder.html">
      <content name="title">Attention Deficit Hyperactivity Disorder</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">ADD</content>
      <content name="altTitle">ADHD</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Hyperactivity</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">What is attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)? &lt;p&gt;ADHD is a neurodevelopmental disorder. It is usually first diagnosed in childhood and often lasts into adulthood. But some people don't get diagnosed with ADHD until they are adults. ADHD involves:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having trouble paying attention (inattention)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having trouble controlling impulsive behaviors (impulsivity)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Being overly active (hyperactivity)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the types of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)? &lt;p&gt;There are three types of ADHD:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mostly Inattentive ADHD. People with this type of ADHD have trouble paying attention and are easily distracted. It's hard for them to organize or finish tasks. They may have trouble following instructions or conversations.
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Mostly Hyperactive-Impulsive ADHD. People with this type of ADHD have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of both hyperactivity and impulsivity:
  &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;With hyperactivity, people feel a need to always be moving. They have trouble sitting still and may fidget and/or talk too much.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;With impulsivity, people have trouble controlling their actions and words. They tend to act on sudden ideas or feelings without thinking about the possible results. They may interrupt others a lot or have trouble waiting their turn.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Combined ADHD. People with this type of ADHD have a mix of inattentive and hyperactive-impulsive &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;. Combined ADHD is the most common type.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;It's normal to sometimes have trouble paying attention or sitting still, especially for children. But people with ADHD have more severe &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; that can sometimes cause serious problems, for example, failing grades for a child or a job loss for an adult. The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; are ongoing and may affect family and social life, too.&lt;/p&gt;What causes attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)?&lt;p&gt;The exact cause of ADHD is unknown. ADHD probably results from a combination of factors, such as genetics and your environment. Researchers are looking at possible environmental factors that might raise the risk of developing ADHD. These factors include brain injuries, nutrition, and social environments.&lt;/p&gt;What are the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)?&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of ADHD depend on the type of ADHD a person has:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;People with &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of attention problems may often:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Miss details or make careless mistakes in schoolwork, at work, or in other activities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have trouble staying focused on play activities or work tasks&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Not seem to listen when spoken to directly&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Find it hard to follow instructions or finish tasks, or may start but get easily sidetracked&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have trouble being organized, keeping belongings in order, and managing time&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Avoid doing tasks that require long periods of mental effort&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lose important items, such as books, wallets, keys, eyeglasses, and cellphones&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Forget about doing daily activities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;People with &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of hyperactivity-impulsivity may often:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fidget and squirm while seated &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Get up when staying seated is expected, such as at school or work&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Run around or climb when it's not appropriate (children) or feel restless (teens and adults)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have trouble doing quiet activities&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Be constantly moving or "on the go"&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Talk much more than is normal&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Blurt out answers before questions are completed&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have trouble waiting for their turn&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Interrupt others for example during conversations or games&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;People with combined ADHD show a mix of inattention and hyperactivity-impulsivity &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;How is attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD) diagnosed?&lt;p&gt;There is no single test to diagnose ADHD. One step of the process for diagnosing ADHD  involves having a physical exam, including vision tests, hearing tests (for children and adults), and other tests to rule out other problems with &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; like ADHD. Other problems with similar &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; include anxiety, depression, sleep problems, and certain types of learning disabilities.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The process also involves a thorough medical history and family history.  And it usually includes using standardized ADHD &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptom&lt;/span&gt; checklists, questionnaires, and/or interview questions. These tools have rating scales (scoring systems) that help the provider see if a person's &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; and history fit a &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;diagnosis&lt;/span&gt; of ADHD.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To make a &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;diagnosis&lt;/span&gt; of ADHD, the provider needs to have found all of these things:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Several &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of ADHD that began before age 12.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Several &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of inattention and/or hyperactivity-impulsivity that have lasted for at least 6 months and cause serious problems:&lt;/li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;For children up to age 16, there must be at least 6 ongoing &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;For people 17 and older, there must be at least 5 ongoing &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Symptoms&lt;/span&gt; that happen in 2 or more settings, for example, at home and at work or school.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Symptoms&lt;/span&gt; that clearly get in the way of functioning well at school, work, and/or in social situations.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Symptoms&lt;/span&gt; aren't caused by another mental health disorder.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the treatments for attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)?&lt;p&gt;Although there is no cure for ADHD, treatments may help reduce &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; and improve functioning. ADHD is commonly treated with:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Medicines.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Psychotherapy (talk therapy), including behavior therapy.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Education or training for parents to give them the skills and strategies to help their child. This is especially important for younger children.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A combination of these treatments.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Good treatment plans will include close monitoring, follow-ups, and making changes, if needed, along the way.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Having a healthy lifestyle, such as healthy eating and regular exercise, may also help manage &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;For school-aged children, school support is important. This could include classroom-based behavioral interventions such as behavior management plans or teaching your child organizational and study skills. It may also include accommodations such as specific seating in the classroom, reduced classwork, or extended time on tests and exams.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Mental Health &lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Attention Deficit Disorder with Hyperactivity</content>
      <content name="groupName">Children and Teenagers</content>
      <content name="groupName">Mental Health and Behavior</content>
      <content name="groupName">Brain and Nerves</content>
      <content name="snippet">What is attention deficit hyperactivity disorder (ADHD)?  ADHD is a neurodevelopmental disorder. It is usually first diagnosed in childhood and often lasts  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="5" url="https://medlineplus.gov/autoimmunediseases.html">
      <content name="title">Autoimmune Diseases</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Autoinflammatory Disorders</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">What are autoimmune diseases?&lt;p&gt;Your immune system protects you from disease and infection by attacking germs that get into your body, such as viruses and bacteria. Your immune system can tell that the germs aren't part of you, so it destroys them. If you have an autoimmune disease, your immune system attacks the healthy cells of your organs and tissues by mistake.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;There are more than 80 types of autoimmune diseases. They can affect almost any part of your body. For example, alopecia areata is an autoimmune disease of the skin that causes hair loss. Autoimmune hepatitis affects the liver. In type 1 diabetes, the immune system attacks the pancreas.  And in rheumatoid arthritis, the immune system can attack many parts of the body, including the joints, lungs, and eyes.&lt;/p&gt;What causes autoimmune diseases?&lt;p&gt;No one is sure why autoimmune diseases happen. But you can't catch them from other people.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Autoimmune diseases do tend to run in families, which means that certain genes may make some people more likely to develop a problem. Viruses, certain chemicals, and other things in the environment may trigger an autoimmune disease if you already have the genes for it.&lt;/p&gt;Who is at risk for autoimmune diseases?&lt;p&gt;Millions of Americans of all ages have autoimmune diseases. Women develop many types of autoimmune diseases much more often than men. And if you have one autoimmune disease, you are more likely to get another.&lt;/p&gt;What are the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of autoimmune diseases?&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of an autoimmune disease depend on the part of your body that's affected. Many types of autoimmune diseases cause redness, swelling, heat, and pain, which are the signs and &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of inflammation.  But other illnesses can cause the same &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of autoimmune diseases can come and go. During a flare-up, your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; may get severe for a while. Later on, you may have a remission, which means that your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; get better or disappear for a period of time.&lt;/p&gt;How are autoimmune diseases diagnosed?&lt;p&gt;Doctors often have a hard time diagnosing autoimmune diseases. There's usually not a specific test to show whether you have a certain autoimmune disease. And the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; can be confusing. That's because many autoimmune diseases have similar &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms. And some symptoms&lt;/span&gt;, such as muscle aches, are common in many other illnesses. So it can take a long time and some visits to different types of doctors to get a &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;diagnosis&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;To help your doctor find out if an autoimmune disease is causing your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;,:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Learn about the health conditions in your family history.  What health problems did your grandparents, aunts, uncles, and cousins have? Write down what you learn and share it with your doctor.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep track of your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;, including how long they last and what makes them better or worse. Share your notes with your doctor.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;See a specialist who deals with the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; that bother you most. For example, if you have rash, see a dermatologist (skin doctor).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the treatments for autoimmune diseases?&lt;p&gt;The treatment depends on the disease. In most cases, the goal of treatment is to suppress (slow down) your immune system, and ease swelling, redness, and pain from inflammation. Your doctor may give you corticosteroids or other medicines to help you feel better. For some diseases, you may need treatment for the rest of your life.&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Autoimmune Diseases</content>
      <content name="groupName">Immune System</content>
      <content name="snippet">What are autoimmune diseases? Your immune system protects you from disease and infection by attacking germs that get into your body, such as viruses and  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="6" url="https://medlineplus.gov/bipolardisorder.html">
      <content name="title">Bipolar Disorder</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Bi-polar Disorder</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Manic-Depressive Illness</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Manic depression</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">What is bipolar disorder?&lt;p&gt;Bipolar disorder is a mood disorder that can cause intense mood swings:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sometimes you may feel extremely "up," elated, irritable, or energized. This is called a manic episode.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other times you may feel "down," sad, indifferent, or hopeless. This is called a depressive episode.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;You may have both manic and depressive &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; together. This is called a mixed episode.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Along with mood swings, bipolar disorder causes changes in behavior, energy levels, and activity levels.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bipolar disorder used to be called other names, including manic depression and manic-depressive disorder.&lt;/p&gt;What are the types of bipolar disorder?&lt;p&gt;There are three main types of bipolar disorder:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bipolar I disorder involves manic episodes that last at least 7 days or manic &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; so severe that you need immediate hospital care. Depressive episodes are also common. Those often last at least two weeks. This type of bipolar disorder can also involve mixed episodes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bipolar II disorder involves depressive episodes. But instead of full-blown manic episodes, there are episodes of hypomania. Hypomania is a less severe version of mania.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Cyclothymic disorder, or cyclothymia, also involves hypomanic and depressive &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;. But they are not as intense or as long-lasting as hypomanic or depressive episodes. The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; usually last for at least two years in adults and for one year in children and teenagers.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;With any of these types, having four or more episodes of mania or depression in a year is called "rapid cycling."&lt;/p&gt;What causes bipolar disorder?&lt;p&gt;The exact cause of bipolar disorder is unknown. Several factors likely play a role in the disorder. They include genetics, brain structure and function, and your environment.&lt;/p&gt;Who is at risk for bipolar disorder?&lt;p&gt;You are at higher risk for bipolar disorder if you have a close relative who has it. Going through trauma or stressful life events may raise this risk even more.&lt;/p&gt;What are the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of bipolar disorder?&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of bipolar disorder can vary. But they involve mood swings known as mood episodes:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of a manic episode can include
     &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Feeling very up, high, or elated&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Feeling jumpy or wired, more active than usual&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having a very short temper or seeming extremely irritable&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having racing thoughts and talking very fast&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Needing less sleep&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Feeling like you are unusually important, talented, or powerful&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do risky things that show poor judgment, such as eating and drinking too much, spending or giving away a lot of money, or having reckless sex&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt; 
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of a depressive episode can include
    &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Feeling very sad, hopeless, or worthless&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Feeling lonely or isolating yourself from others&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Talking very slowly, feeling like you have nothing to say, or forgetting a lot&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Having little energy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Sleeping too much&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Eating too much or too little&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lack of interest in your usual activities and being unable to do even simple things&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Thinking about death or suicide&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of a mixed episode include both manic and depressive &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; together. For example, you may feel very sad, empty, or hopeless, while at the same time feeling extremely energized.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some people with bipolar disorder may have milder &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;. For example, you may have hypomania instead of mania. With hypomania, you may feel very good and find that you can get a lot done. You may not feel like anything is wrong. But your family and friends may notice your mood swings and changes in activity levels. They may realize that your behavior is unusual for you. After the hypomania, you might have severe depression.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your mood episodes may last a week or two or sometimes longer. During an episode, &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; usually occur every day for most of the day.&lt;/p&gt;How is bipolar disorder diagnosed?&lt;p&gt;To diagnose bipolar disorder, your health care provider may use many tools:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A physical exam&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A medical history, which will include asking about your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;, lifetime history, experiences, and family history&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Medical tests to rule out other conditions&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A mental health evaluation. Your provider may do the evaluation or may refer you to a mental health specialist to get one.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the treatments for bipolar disorder?&lt;p&gt;Treatment can help many people, including those with the most severe forms of bipolar disorder. The main treatments for bipolar disorder include medicines, psychotherapy, or both:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Medicines can help control the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of bipolar disorder. You may need to try several different medicines to find which one works best for you. Some people need to take more than one medicine. It's important to take your medicine consistently. Don't stop taking it without first talking with your provider.  Contact your provider if you have any concerns about side effects from the medicines.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Psychotherapy (talk therapy) can help you recognize and change troubling emotions, thoughts, and behaviors. It can give you and your family support, education, skills, and coping strategies. There are several different types of psychotherapy that may help with bipolar disorder.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other treatment options include:
    &lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Electroconvulsive therapy (ECT), a brain stimulation procedure that can help relieve &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;. It uses a mild electric current and is done while you are under general anesthesia. ECT is most often used for severe bipolar disorder that is not getting better with other treatments. It may also be used when someone needs a treatment that will work more quickly than medicines. This might be when a person has a high risk of suicide or is catatonic (unresponsive).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Repetitive transcranial magnetic stimulation (rTMS), a brain stimulation procedure that uses magnetic waves to relieve depression. It is not as powerful as ECT, but with rTMS, you don't need general anesthesia. It also has a low risk of negative effects on your memory and thinking.
  &lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Light therapy has been shown to be effective for seasonal affective disorder (SAD). Many people with bipolar disorder also find that their depression gets worse during certain seasons, usually in the fall and winter. Light therapy may help with their &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Healthy lifestyle changes, such as getting regular exercise, having a consistent sleep schedule, and keeping a mood journal, can also help with your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;    
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bipolar disorder is a lifelong illness. But long-term, ongoing treatment can help manage your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; and enable you to live a healthy, successful life.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Mental Health&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Bipolar Disorder</content>
      <content name="groupName">Mental Health and Behavior</content>
      <content name="snippet">What is bipolar disorder? Bipolar disorder is a mood disorder that can cause intense mood swings: Sometimes you may feel extremely "up," elated, irritable,  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="7" url="https://medlineplus.gov/carpaltunnelsyndrome.html">
      <content name="title">Carpal Tunnel Syndrome</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Median nerve entrapment</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">What is carpal tunnel syndrome?&lt;p&gt;Carpal tunnel syndrome is the name for a group of problems that includes numbness, tingling, weakness, or pain in your wrist or hand. It's a very common condition that happens when a nerve in your wrist becomes squeezed.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;The carpal tunnel is a narrow opening between the bones in your wrist and the ligament that holds them together.  A nerve, called the median nerve, runs from your lower arm through the carpal tunnel and into your hand. This nerve provides feeling to your thumb and first three fingers.  It also helps you move your thumb.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Tendons also run from your lower arm, through the carpal tunnel, and into your hand. The tendons connect your finger bones to muscles in your arm, so you can bend your fingers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If the tendons become swollen or irritated inside the carpal tunnel, they may press on the nerve. The squeezed nerve may not work well, which can lead to numbness, weakness, and other &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of carpal tunnel syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;What causes carpal tunnel syndrome?&lt;p&gt;In certain cases, the cause of carpal tunnel syndrome is unknown. But it usually happens from a combination of things that affect the structures in your wrist, such as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Injury to your wrist that causes swelling, such as a sprain or broken bone&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Health conditions that can affect your nerves, joints, or other parts of your wrist, for example:
	&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Diabetes.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rheumatoid arthritis.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A cyst or tumor in your wrist.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Changes in  certain hormones, which may cause swelling from extra fluid in your body. Examples include an underactive thyroid gland (hypothyroidism), pregnancy and menopause.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Problems with the way your wrist is formed.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Doing the same wrist and hand movements over and over, such as: 
	&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Assembly line work.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Carpentry or using tools that vibrate.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Knitting, gardening, or sports, such as golf.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Researchers aren't sure whether long-term typing or computer use leads to carpal tunnel syndrome.&lt;/p&gt;Who is more likely to develop carpal tunnel syndrome?&lt;p&gt;Carpal tunnel syndrome usually happens only in adults. You're more likely to develop it if you:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are a woman. Women are three times more likely to have carpal tunnel syndrome than men.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have a health condition that may affect structures in your wrist.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do activities with repeated hand motions.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have had a wrist injury.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have a close relative who has had carpal tunnel syndrome, such as a parent, brother or sister.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of carpal tunnel syndrome?&lt;p&gt;You may feel numbness, tingling or burning in your fingers, especially in your thumb, index, and middle fingers. &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Symptoms&lt;/span&gt; often affect both hands.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;In the early stages, &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; usually:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Start slowly in your dominant hand (the one you write with)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Happen at night if you sleep with your wrists bent&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;As &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; get worse, you may notice:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tingling, pain, or weakness with certain activities, such as driving or holding a phone&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Difficulty grasping or holding small things&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Feeling like your fingers are swollen when they're not&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Without treatment, you could lose feeling in some fingers and have permanent weakness in your thumb. But early &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;diagnosis&lt;/span&gt; and treatment can help prevent lasting damage.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; 


&lt;/p&gt;How is carpal tunnel syndrome diagnosed?&lt;p&gt;To find out if you have carpal tunnel syndrome, your health care provider will:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ask about your medical history&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ask about your family health history&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Do a physical exam&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Order tests if needed, such as:
	&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lab tests to look for diseases that may damage nerves&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;X-rays to look for broken bones or arthritis&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tests to measure the electrical activity in your nerves and muscles&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ultrasound to check the nerve in the carpal tunnel&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the treatments for carpal tunnel syndrome?&lt;p&gt;It's easier to treat carpal tunnel syndrome early on, so you should start treatment as soon as possible. Your provider will first treat any health conditions you have that may cause your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;. The next step would be treatments for carpal tunnel syndrome. They may include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wrist splints (usually worn at night).&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Rest.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Medicines to reduce swelling and pain:&lt;/li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Over-the-counter pain relievers, such as aspirin, ibuprofen, and naproxen sodium.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Prescriptionsteroids, either pills or an injection (shot) into your wrist.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Other therapies (complementary and integrative medicine). Research shows that yoga may help with pain and weakness. Some people may find acupuncture and chiropractic care helpful, but research hasn't shown that these therapies can improve carpal tunnel syndrome. If you want to try other therapies, talk with your provider first.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Surgery to make more space in the carpal tunnel. Surgery may be an option if your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; are severe and other treatments don't work. It involves cutting the wrist ligament to take pressure off the nerve.  Recovery may take months. Carpal tunnel syndrome rarely comes back after surgery, but mild &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; may last.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;Can carpal tunnel syndrome be prevented?&lt;p&gt;You may help prevent carpal tunnel syndrome if you protect your wrists:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Use good posture to keep your wrists in a natural position.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Keep your hands warm to keep your muscles flexible. Fingerless gloves may help.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Take work breaks and vary your tasks.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Stretch and exercise your hands and wrists.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Organize your workspace and tools to reduce strain on your hands and wrists.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Carpal Tunnel Syndrome</content>
      <content name="groupName">Bones, Joints and Muscles</content>
      <content name="groupName">Brain and Nerves</content>
      <content name="snippet">What is carpal tunnel syndrome? Carpal tunnel syndrome is the name for a group of problems that includes numbness, tingling, weakness, or pain in your  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="8" url="https://medlineplus.gov/celiacdisease.html">
      <content name="title">Celiac Disease</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Gluten Intolerance</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Gluten-Sensitive Enteropathy</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Nontropical Sprue</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Celiac sprue</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">What is celiac disease?&lt;p&gt;Celiac disease is a chronic (long-term) digestive and immune disorder that damages your small intestine. The damage may prevent your body from absorbing vitamins, minerals, and other nutrients from the food you eat. This can lead to malnutrition and other serious health problems&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Celiac disease is triggered by eating foods that contain gluten. Gluten is a protein found in wheat, barley, rye, and other grains. It may also be in other products like vitamins and supplements, hair and skin products, toothpastes, and lip balm.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Celiac disease is different from gluten sensitivity. Both involve problems with gluten and can cause some of the same &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;, such as abdominal (belly) pain and fatigue. But gluten sensitivity does not damage the small intestine like celiac disease does.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt; Wheat allergy, a type of food allergy, is also different. With both celiac disease and wheat allergy, your immune system is reacting to wheat. But with wheat allergy, you can have some different &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;, such as itchy eyes or trouble breathing. And a wheat allergy will not cause long-term damage to the small intestine.&lt;/p&gt;What causes celiac disease?&lt;p&gt;The exact cause of celiac disease is not known. Research suggests that celiac disease only happens in people who have certain genes and eat food that contains gluten. Researchers are studying other factors that may play a role in causing the disease.&lt;/p&gt;Who is more likely to develop celiac disease?&lt;p&gt;Celiac disease is more common if you:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have a family member who has the disease&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Have Down syndrome, Turner syndrome, or Williams syndrome&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are White&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Are female&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of celiac disease?&lt;p&gt;The &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of celiac disease can be different from person to person. Sometimes the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; may come and go. Some people may not notice any &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some of the possible &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; affect your digestive system. Digestive &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; are more common in children than in adults. The digestive &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bloating (feeling fullness or swelling in your belly)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Chronic (long-term) diarrhea or greasy, bulky, unusually bad-smelling stool (poop)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Constipation&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Gas&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lactose intolerance because of damage to the small intestine&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nausea and vomiting&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pain in the abdomen (belly)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Weight loss in adults, or not enough weight gain in children&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some people with celiac disease have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; that affect other parts of the body, such as:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Fatigue&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Depression and anxiety&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Irritability (in children)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Dermatitis herpetiformis, an itchy rash with blisters (mainly in adults)&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bone or joint pain&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;&lt;span class="qt0"&gt;Symptoms&lt;/span&gt; involving the mouth, such as canker sores or dry mouth&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What other problems can celiac disease cause?&lt;p&gt;Over time, celiac disease can cause other health problems, especially if it is not treated. These problems can include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Malnutrition&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Anemia, especially iron-deficiency anemia&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bone loss&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nervous system problems such as headaches, balance problems, or peripheral neuropathy&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Reproductive problems, such as missed menstrual periods and miscarriages in women and infertility in men and women&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;How is celiac disease diagnosed?&lt;p&gt;If you have &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of celiac disease, your health care provider will look for signs that you might have celiac disease. To do this, your provider will get your medical and family history and do a physical exam.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;If your provider thinks that you could have celiac disease, you will have some tests. Providers most often use blood tests and biopsies of the small intestine to diagnose celiac disease. The biopsy would be done during an upper gastrointestinal (GI) endoscopy. For this procedure, your provider uses an endoscope (a flexible tube with a camera) to see the lining of your esophagus, stomach, and small intestine. It also allows your provider to take a sample of tissue for a biopsy.&lt;/p&gt;What are the treatments for celiac disease?&lt;p&gt;The treatment for celiac disease is following a gluten-free diet for the rest of your life. Sticking with a gluten-free diet will treat or prevent many of the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; and other health problems caused by celiac disease. In most cases, it can also heal damage in the small intestine and prevent more damage. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Your provider may refer you to a registered dietician (a nutrition expert) who can help you learn how to eat a healthy diet without gluten. You will also need to avoid all hidden sources of gluten, such as certain supplements, cosmetics, toothpaste, etc. Reading product labels can sometimes help you avoid gluten. If a label doesn't tell you what is in a product, check with the company that makes the product for an ingredients list. Don't just assume that a product is gluten-free if it doesn't mention it.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Institute of Diabetes and Digestive and Kidney Diseases&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Celiac Disease</content>
      <content name="groupName">Digestive System</content>
      <content name="groupName">Metabolic Problems</content>
      <content name="snippet">What is celiac disease? Celiac disease is a chronic (long-term) digestive and immune disorder that damages your small intestine. The damage may prevent  ... </content>
    </document>
    <document rank="9" url="https://medlineplus.gov/chronicbronchitis.html">
      <content name="title">Chronic Bronchitis</content>
      <content name="organizationName">National Library of Medicine</content>
      <content name="altTitle">Bronchitis</content>
      <content name="FullSummary">What is chronic bronchitis?&lt;p&gt;Chronic bronchitis is a type of COPD (chronic obstructive pulmonary disease). COPD is a group of lung diseases that make it hard to breathe and get worse over time. The other main type of COPD is emphysema. Most people with COPD have both emphysema and chronic bronchitis, but how severe each type is can be different from person to person.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chronic bronchitis is inflammation (swelling) and irritation of the bronchial tubes. These tubes are the airways that carry air to and from the air sacs in your lungs. The irritation of the tubes causes mucus to build up. This mucus and the swelling of the tubes make it harder for your lungs to move oxygen in and carbon dioxide out of your body.&lt;/p&gt;What causes chronic bronchitis?&lt;p&gt;The cause of chronic bronchitis is usually long-term exposure to irritants that damage your lungs and airways. In the United States, cigarette smoke is the main cause. Pipe, cigar, and other types of tobacco smoke can also cause chronic bronchitis, especially if you inhale them.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Exposure to other inhaled irritants can contribute to chronic bronchitis. These include secondhand smoke, air pollution, and chemical fumes or dusts from the environment or workplace.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Rarely, a genetic condition called alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency can play a role in causing chronic bronchitis.&lt;/p&gt;Who is at risk for chronic bronchitis?&lt;p&gt;The risk factors for chronic bronchitis include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Smoking. This the main risk factor. Up to 75% of people who have chronic bronchitis smoke or used to smoke.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Long-term exposure to other lung irritants, such as secondhand smoke, air pollution, and chemical fumes and dusts from the environment or workplace.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Age. Most people who have chronic bronchitis are at least 40 years old when their &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; begin.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Genetics. This includes alpha-1 antitrypsin deficiency, which is a genetic condition. Also, smokers who get chronic bronchitis are more likely to get it if they have a family history of COPD.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; of chronic bronchitis?&lt;p&gt;At first, you may have no &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; or only mild &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;. As the disease gets worse, your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; usually become more severe. They can include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Frequent coughing or a cough that produces a lot mucus&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Wheezing&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A whistling or squeaky sound when you breathe&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Shortness of breath, especially with physical activity&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Tightness in your chest&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;Some people with chronic bronchitis get frequent respiratory infections such as colds and the flu. In severe cases, chronic bronchitis can cause weight loss, weakness in your lower muscles, and swelling in your ankles, feet, or legs.&lt;/p&gt;How is chronic bronchitis diagnosed?&lt;p&gt;Your health care provider may use many tools to make a &lt;span class="qt1"&gt;diagnosis&lt;/span&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A medical history, which includes asking about your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;A family history&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Various tests, such as lung function tests, a chest x-ray or CT scan, and blood tests&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;What are the treatments for chronic bronchitis?&lt;p&gt;There is no cure for chronic bronchitis. However, treatments can help with &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;, slow the progress of the disease, and improve your ability to stay active. There are also treatments to prevent or treat complications of the disease. Treatments include:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Lifestyle changes, such as
	&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Quitting smoking if you are a smoker. This is the most important step you can take to treat chronic bronchitis.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Avoiding secondhand smoke and places where you might breathe in other lung irritants&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Ask your health care provider for an eating plan that will meet your nutritional needs. Also ask about how much physical activity you can do. Physical activity can strengthen the muscles that help you breathe and improve your overall wellness.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Medicines, such as
	&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;Bronchodilators, which relax the muscles around your airways. This helps open your airways and makes breathing easier. Most bronchodilators are taken through an inhaler. In more severe cases, the inhaler may also contain steroids to reduce inflammation.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Vaccines for the flu and pneumococcal pneumonia, since people with chronic bronchitis are at higher risk for serious problems from these diseases.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Antibiotics if you get a bacterial or viral lung infection&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Oxygen therapy, if you have severe chronic bronchitis and low levels of oxygen in your blood. Oxygen therapy can help you breathe better. You may need extra oxygen all the time or only at certain times.&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Pulmonary rehabilitation, which is a program that helps improve the well-being of people who have chronic breathing problems. It may include&lt;/li&gt;&lt;ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;An exercise program&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Disease management training&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Nutritional counseling&lt;/li&gt;&lt;li&gt;Psychological counseling&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;li&gt;A lung transplant, as a last resort for people who have severe &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; that have not gotten better with medicines&lt;/li&gt;&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you have chronic bronchitis, it's important to know when and where to get help for your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;. You should get emergency care if you have severe &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt;, such as trouble catching your breath or talking. Call your health care provider if your &lt;span class="qt0"&gt;symptoms&lt;/span&gt; are getting worse or if you have signs of an infection, such as a fever.&lt;/p&gt;Can chronic bronchitis be prevented?&lt;p&gt;Since smoking causes most cases of chronic bronchitis, the best way to prevent it is to not smoke. It's also important to try to avoid lung irritants such as secondhand smoke, air pollution, chemical fumes, and dusts.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;


&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;NIH: National Heart, Lung, and Blood Institute&lt;/p&gt;</content>
      <content name="mesh">Bronchitis, Chronic</content>
      <content name="groupName">Infections</content>
      <content name="groupName">Lungs and Breathing</content>
      <content name="snippet">What is chronic bronchitis? Chronic bronchitis is a type of COPD (chronic obstructive pulmonary disease). COPD is a group of lung diseases that make it  ... </content>
    </document>
  </list>
</nlmSearchResult>
